

Contact Information

Location

Iran, Tehran, Pasdaran

Nationality

Iranian

Email work.koohkan@gmail.com

Phone & Whatsapp +989391840688

Languages

English | Persian | German

About me

I am an iOS developer with experience in building iOS apps using UIKit and SwiftUI and web applications using Swift NIO, I have a deep experience in the financial industry, also very interested in user interface design and used to work with Sketch, Figma and Procreate to design apps and digital arts. My best abilities are to solve complex algorithms, complex system architecture design, process automation, integration with Backend services, improving user interface performance, and optimizing systems memory management. I always check benchmark tests results to choose best practice methods or making one to do my tasks, I believe every word of my code should try to be at its best, also i love principles and breaking them to find creatively

Core Skills

answers.



Fastlane CircleCl

Tools & Technologies



Apple WWDC Point-Free

- Objc.io
- · Hacking With Swift
- Swift by Sundell
- Raywenderlich Swift blog and forum
- dotConferences
- My followings on Medium · Channels on Youtube

Mohammadreza Koohkan

iOS Developer



https://mohamadreza.com/

Achievements

GitHub

iOS and Shell scripts | 11 Projects | 106 stars

Link: https://github.com/mohamadrezakoohkan

Distribution: All libraries have unit tests and documentation and supports

Carthage, Cocoapods and Swift Package Manager CI/CD: Unit tests, generating documentation and deploy universal

XCFramework are done by Github Actions

Stack Overflow

2005 Reputation | 52 Answers | 15 Questions

Link: https://stackoverflow.com/users/9706268

Education

Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering

Islamic Azad University - Iran | 2015 - 2020

iOS Development Sharif University of Technology - Iran | Feb 2016

Credential ID SUT-IT-0028148

OKR Champion

UXER School - Spain | May 2022

Credential ID 50252450

Design Patterns

Most used design patterns

Composition over Inheritence to keep SOLID safe

SwiftUI:

- TCA for small applications, I believe it adds complexity when it comes to large applications - MVI with Store for business logic
- For UIKit based applications:

- MVVM with Coordinator and RxSwift for being event driven - MVC as it is most used in Cocoa by Apple
- For mixed UIKit and SwiftUI applications:

- MVI with Presenter for business logic

Work Experiences

Mobile Engineer Playtomic - Madrid, Spain | Apr 2022 - Present | Full time

Playtomic is Europe's largest sports booking app and SaaS for sport

venues. I was mainly responsible for Platform, Financial and Premium features. Since I had the chance to work with the Android platform in my previous job

for a while, I could get this Mobile Engineer role who is able to work on both iOS and Android platforms. One of challenges I tackled during this experience was to migrate our big iOS project from CocoaPods to tuist in 3 months as well as migrating CI/CD workflows and writing scripts to increase Development experience. I received nice feedbacks from my colleges and tech lead about how well I executed this objective. Senior iOS Engineer

Socialteq - Turkey & Qatar | Jul 2020 - Apr 2022 | Full time

SwiftUI for iOS.

Senior iOS Developer

Karo is a leading IT Consultancy in Qatar and Turkey. The company also has its own projects in field of e-commerce, food

ordering and cryptocurrency exchange.

I worked on E-Commerce and Food Ordering app with Swift in a team of 3. After completing our project, we (Android and iOS team) came to the conclusion that a large amount of our code was duplicate and could be

shared between the platforms as business logic layer. So we learned Flutter, since Flutter was not yet operational and enterprise productionready, we switched to learning React Native and KMM (Kotlin Multiplatform Mobile). In the final vote, KMM won according to the votes of the members. We decided to do next project, which is a cryptocurrency exchange using

KMM for shared logics with UI Framework of Compose for android and

SmartChef - Switzerland | Nov 2019 - Apr 2020 | Contract

"SMART CHEF" is the first "Food Social Network" in Switzerland.

This was an outsourced project from a Swiss company based in Basel. By

the time I joined the project, it had been done by an Indian agency.

The quality of codes and documentation was extremely low. I took over this project and refactored this project in iterative way.

After 4 months of development process, the Swiss company postponed its

Mid iOS Developer

work due to the spread of the corona virus and lack of funding at that time.

Hamyan - Iran | Dec 2018 - Mar 2020 | Full time

Hamyan is a neo banking startup with loan funds and lending lottery fund. Some of my objectives:

- Participate in a shot-down migration (backend framework, database, design fully re-designed)

- Providing efficient balacing algorithms

- Cross-functionality with working both with Design and iOS team - Code review, scripting, CI/CD workflows
- MVC as arch, RxSwift, Alamofire with Moya and RealmSwift

Junior iOS Developer

AHS IT Solutions is IT Consultancy company which turns customer ideas

AHS IT Solutions - Iran | Feb 2016 - Feb 2017 | Full time

into software products. As a novice iOS Software Developer, this was my biggest chance to get

hired at this fast growing company. I had support from other senior collegues to help me grow faster in my career as well as writing spagetti code from my side was no concern to the team.